<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Erik Blomquist on KORKEN</title>
    <link>https://www.korken.xyz/tags/erik-blomquist/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Erik Blomquist on KORKEN</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 12:17:21 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.korken.xyz/tags/erik-blomquist/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Infrastructure for StackStorm</title>
      <link>https://www.korken.xyz/posts/terraform-infrastructure-chatops/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 12:17:21 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.korken.xyz/posts/terraform-infrastructure-chatops/</guid>
      <description>We are going to create an infrastructure with Terraform that automatically installs StackStorm onto our instance.
 Variables  AWS StackStorm   Main  Provider AMI Security Groups EC2 Instance   Execute  Variables AWS   Create a new file to store our variables called variables.tf and open it with your favorite text editor.
  We need to add variables for our AWS keys and we can do so with the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Create A Customized AMI with Packer</title>
      <link>https://www.korken.xyz/posts/create-ami-with-packer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 11:52:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.korken.xyz/posts/create-ami-with-packer/</guid>
      <description>Download Packer Template Validate and Build  Download Packer Packer is a lightweight tool that is used to create pre-configured operating systems also called images (AMIs). You can download packer using the link or alternative methods below.
https://www.packer.io/downloads.html
Alternative methods
 OSX: brew install packer Windows: choco install packer  Template Packer uses templates in the format of JSON in order to configure and create images.
 variables are necessary so that we can pass our AWS credentials for authentication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Install Prometheus with Ansible on Amazon Linux.</title>
      <link>https://www.korken.xyz/posts/prometheus-playbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 18:40:23 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.korken.xyz/posts/prometheus-playbook/</guid>
      <description>Prometheus We have previously downloaded, installed and configured Prometheus manually and it was a little tidious. We are going to create a playbook with Ansible that automates the process for us.
  Create a new file with the name setup_prometheus.yml and add the following to update the yum repo and to create a prometheus user:
 --- - hosts: all become: true tasks: - name: Update yum repo yum: name: &#39;*&#39; state: latest - name: Create Prometheus user shell: | useradd --no-create-home --shell /bin/false prometheus mkdir /etc/prometheus mkdir /var/lib/prometheus chown prometheus:prometheus /etc/prometheus chown prometheus:prometheus /var/lib/prometheus    Next step is to download, extract and install prometheus and we can do that like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Run Ansible Playbooks Remotely</title>
      <link>https://www.korken.xyz/posts/ansible-remotely/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 10:11:03 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.korken.xyz/posts/ansible-remotely/</guid>
      <description>Ansible is a great automation platform that allows you to control and configure multiple instances from your local machine without having to login to them.
 Pre-req Install Ansible Hosts file Test Playbook  Pre-req I have one Amazon Linux instance running that I will make changes to. You&amp;rsquo;ll need the following:
 Public IP to your instance PEM key  Install Ansible Make sure that your running instance have Ansible installed already or run the following:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>